CONTACT ME AT lisa@gmail.com or 8927489392

TOOLS & TECH

Python SOL

Microsoft Excel

Tableau

Apache Spark

GitHub

Google Data Studio

Google Analytics

Adobe Photoshop

DBeaver

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Data Preprocessing and EDA Statistical Data Analysis inclu testing Statistical Hypothesis Quantitative Research Metho Data Visualization and report Web Mining

Business Analytics (KPI analyt cohort analytics, A/B testing, product funnels) Machine learning (Forecasts

Predictions)

EDUCATION & COURSES

The Ural Federal University Computer science 2013 - 2014 Practicum by Yandex: Data Ana 2020

HackerRank: SQL Certificate, 2 Stepik: Basic Statistics, 2021 Coursera: Apache Spark (TM) S for Data Analysts, 2021 Maxim Gorky Institute of Litera and Creative Writing | 2012 - 20 M.A. in Literary Translation

GPA: 3.8 / 4

LANGUAGES

LISA POLOTCKAIA

DATA ANALYST

PROFILE

Detail- and process-oriented Data Analyst with Python and SQL proficiency. Have startup experience, a history of project presenting, strong research & analytical skills. Hold M.A. in Translation, finished 1 year of Computer Science study and 9month Data Analyst Yandex100 Program

WORK EXPERIENCE

Outsourcing data analyst

Pinsteps | Nov 2020 - present

- Conducted projects on cohort analysis, conversion evaluation
- Assessed user activity and retention rates
- Created user engagement reports that helped to establish app development direction

Interviewer

Israel Way | Sept 2018 - Feb 2020

- Conducted surveys of MASA participants and highlighted issues to be modified due to participants experience
- Created reports, presentations using Google Workspace tools

Video algorithm specialist

Minute.ly_ | Nov 2019 - Jan 2020

 Trained AI Algorithm for selecting highlights of video materials representing content of customer's websites

Program coordinator

Israel StartUp Tour | Sept 2018 - Feb 2020

• Developed and organized tours on Israeli startups for foreign entrepreneurs that were focused on startup networking and led to successful business corporations

PROJECT EXAMPLES (clickable)

KPI analytics and marketing expansions optimization

• Examined user behavior, conducted cohort analyze establishing cohorts' KPI and thus indicated the most profitable advertising sources, which helped to develop further advertisement strategy

A/B testing

• Verified A/B test conduction correctness and used its results to define more user engaging website version. Used user conversion funnels & statistical hypotheses tests to confirm the conclusions

Churn forecasting (machine learning)

• Preprocessed and explored the data, indicated inner patterns and correlation and used LogisticRegression, RandomForest and K-Means to successfully identify clients prone to churn

Identify ing inefficient mobile operators

• Created a method to evaluate operators effectiveness. Successfully **implemented** it, identified ineffective operators and proved conclusions with statistical tests